<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-15T23:20:00+05:30</updated><id>https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saurabh Gandhi</title><subtitle>The story and thoughts of Saurabh Gandhi</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Cold Email That Landed Me a Job at Upstox</title><link href="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/2022/12/21/cold-email/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cold Email That Landed Me a Job at Upstox" /><published>2022-12-21T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-12-21T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/2022/12/21/cold-email</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/2022/12/21/cold-email/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-cold-email-that-landed-me-my-dream-job-at-upstox">The Cold Email That Landed Me My Dream Job at Upstox</h1>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Originally published on my LinkedIn.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Two years ago I hit <strong>Send</strong> on the message below.
Subject line: <strong>“A hustler who wants to join the rocketship at Upstox.”</strong></p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>From: Saurabh Gandhi &lt;pgp17.saurabhg@spjimr.org&gt;
To: Shrini Viswanath
Date: 16 Sep 2020, 10:33 PM
Subject: An Hustler who wants to join the rocketship at Upstox

Hi Shrini,

I am writing to you to check if I can be a part of the team at Upstox.
But before I start my elevator pitch to sell myself and convince you of how good I am, I want to congratulate you for the amazing product that you have built.
Having been a customer myself I love how Upstox has cut all the clutter and allows its users to focus on what matters most.
(There are a few bugs on the iOS app but I am a promoter if you do a NPS on me.)
No wonder the new WFH millennial Indian is taking greater interest in trading and investing.

To tell you about myself, in short, I am a hustler and problem solver.
Building delightful customer experiences with a mix of technology, design and data is what I love to do.
I started out as a computer-science engineer, joined the only startup that visited my not-so-well-known engineering school, and built the entire backend platform from scratch (microservices, APIs, Django, Python).
After the company was acquired I started an agritech venture that aimed to be an Amazon for farmers.
Before demonetisation we had two crore rupees in GMV in a fully bootstrapped setup.
I learned build-measure-learn, growth hacking, lots of SQL, and most important, customer empathy.

I then completed an MBA at SP Jain Institute of Management with a focus on analytics and product management and took advanced courses at Carnegie Mellon’s Tepper School of Business.
Now I am at Ola Electric, helping build an electric two-wheeler.
Three months ago I was solving for the energy infrastructure, which taught me that throwing money at problems only hides them for a while.

Fintech for Bharat (I come from a small town) is what I want to do next.
Upstox has delighted me during the six months I have been a customer (I used Nirmal Bang for the past eight years) and I want to board this rocket ship.
Product and growth are the roles I would love to pursue.
I noticed three open positions on your job board.

Please let me know if I could add value to your team.
I have attached my CV.

Regards,
Saurabh Gandhi
+91-9767845670

Attachment: Saurabh_Gandhi.pdf
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>That email changed everything.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="why-i-wrote-it">Why I Wrote It</h2>

<p>I was working on electric two-wheelers at Ola Electric but craved a role that blended product, growth, and fintech. Upstox ticked every box. Instead of waiting for a job post or a referral I wrote straight to the co-founder.</p>

<h3 id="how-i-framed-it">How I Framed It</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Quick hook</strong>
I opened with genuine praise for the product and flagged a small bug. It showed I was already a power user.</li>
  <li><strong>Crisp story</strong>
Three paragraphs covered my coding roots, a startup I had worked on, and an MBA focused on product.</li>
  <li><strong>Clear value</strong>
I linked my skills to gaps I spotted on their job board and asked for a chance to prove my worth.</li>
</ol>

<hr />

<p>Today marks two years at a company that feels like home.</p>

<h2 id="lessons-from-the-journey">Lessons From the Journey</h2>

<h3 id="1-passion-beats-polish">1. Passion Beats Polish</h3>

<p>A heartfelt note beats a template. I wrote in my own voice and it clicked.</p>

<h3 id="2-own-your-story">2. Own Your Story</h3>

<p>Listing roles is dull. A short narrative is memorable. My email showed a clear arc from coding to product to fintech.</p>

<h3 id="3-ask-boldly-and-politely">3. Ask Boldly and Politely</h3>

<p>People are busy yet they read thoughtful messages. A specific ask and respect for their time can open doors.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="what-happened-after-i-joined">What Happened After I Joined</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Ownership drives me</strong>
Upstox lets me think like an owner and chase outcomes end to end.</li>
  <li><strong>Passion compounds</strong>
Working where finance meets tech keeps me energized every day.</li>
  <li><strong>Culture shapes growth</strong>
The calm guidance of Aditya Vyas and Divye Bokdia and the relentless drive of Sandeep Agrawal and Shruti Kalamdani define how I work and lead.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p><em>Thanks for reading. Questions about cold emails or product roles in fintech? Ping me on LinkedIn and I will be happy to help.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Cold Email That Landed Me My Dream Job at Upstox]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma</title><link href="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma" /><published>2015-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://saurabh-gandhi.github.io/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship/"><![CDATA[<p>Back in January 2015, I started a six-month internship at Zlemma Analytics Pvt. Ltd. in Pune. I was a software intern, fresh off a campus placement, and full of nerves. But deep down, I had a feeling I’d do well. Looking back, I can’t help but smile at how much I grew during that time.</p>

<p>Zlemma was a Series A funded startup with a development team in Pune and a sales office in Palo Alto. The company had patented algorithms to help tech firms hire STEM talent. The founder was an IIT-Bombay alum, and the team was a strong mix of IIT grads and smart folks from tier-two colleges in Maharashtra. It was one of the most driven and talented teams I had seen.</p>

<p>Here are six lessons I took away from that experience:</p>

<h2 id="1-find-mentors">1. Find Mentors</h2>

<p>I got lucky. My mentor was one of the most grounded and gifted people in the company. He didn’t hand me solutions. Instead, he nudged me in the right direction and let me figure things out. I learned more from him in those six months than in four years of engineering college.</p>

<h2 id="2-speak-up-ask-questions">2. Speak Up. Ask Questions.</h2>

<p>No question is too dumb. Especially when you’re starting out. Use this time to ask freely — you won’t always get that chance as you move up.</p>

<h2 id="3-take-on-more-than-expected">3. Take On More Than Expected</h2>

<p>I worked on four projects when I only needed to complete one for college credit. I didn’t know what the benchmark was for interns, but I kept taking more because each task taught me something new.</p>

<h2 id="4-start-building-your-network">4. Start Building Your Network</h2>

<p>Getting a good internship is just the beginning. Be proactive. Talk to people. Learn from them. Make an impression. Everyone respects someone who creates their own opportunities.</p>

<h2 id="5-ask-for-feedback">5. Ask for Feedback</h2>

<p>Don’t wait for review cycles. Ask where you can do better — from your mentor, your teammates, anyone who can help. Then work on that feedback. That’s how you grow.</p>

<h2 id="6-enjoy-the-ride">6. Enjoy the Ride</h2>

<p>Internships aren’t just about work. With your first bit of income, do something fun. Try new things. Make memories. You’ll never get this time back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="blog" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="introduction" /><category term="blogging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in January 2015, I started a six-month internship at Zlemma Analytics Pvt. Ltd. in Pune. I was a software intern, fresh off a campus placement, and full of nerves. But deep down, I had a feeling I’d do well. Looking back, I can’t help but smile at how much I grew during that time.]]></summary></entry></feed>