<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-21T16:58:17+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saurabh Gandhi</title><subtitle>The story and thoughts of Saurabh Gandhi</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma" /><published>2015-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/blog/2015/07/06/zlemma-internship/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-i-learned-from-my-internship-at-zlemma">What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma</h1>

<p>Back in January 2015, I started a six-month internship at Zlemma Analytics Pvt. Ltd. in Pune. I was a software intern, fresh off a campus placement, and full of nerves. But deep down, I had a feeling I’d do well. Looking back, I can’t help but smile at how much I grew during that time.</p>

<p>Zlemma was a Series A funded startup with a development team in Pune and a sales office in Palo Alto. The company had patented algorithms to help tech firms hire STEM talent. The founder was an IIT-Bombay alum, and the team was a strong mix of IIT grads and smart folks from tier-two colleges in Maharashtra. It was one of the most driven and talented teams I had seen.</p>

<p>Here are six lessons I took away from that experience:</p>

<h2 id="1-find-mentors">1. Find Mentors</h2>

<p>I got lucky. My mentor was one of the most grounded and gifted people in the company. He didn’t hand me solutions. Instead, he nudged me in the right direction and let me figure things out. I learned more from him in those six months than in four years of engineering college.</p>

<h2 id="2-speak-up-ask-questions">2. Speak Up. Ask Questions.</h2>

<p>No question is too dumb. Especially when you’re starting out. Use this time to ask freely — you won’t always get that chance as you move up.</p>

<h2 id="3-take-on-more-than-expected">3. Take On More Than Expected</h2>

<p>I worked on four projects when I only needed to complete one for college credit. I didn’t know what the benchmark was for interns, but I kept taking more because each task taught me something new.</p>

<h2 id="4-start-building-your-network">4. Start Building Your Network</h2>

<p>Getting a good internship is just the beginning. Be proactive. Talk to people. Learn from them. Make an impression. Everyone respects someone who creates their own opportunities.</p>

<h2 id="5-ask-for-feedback">5. Ask for Feedback</h2>

<p>Don’t wait for review cycles. Ask where you can do better — from your mentor, your teammates, anyone who can help. Then work on that feedback. That’s how you grow.</p>

<h2 id="6-enjoy-the-ride">6. Enjoy the Ride</h2>

<p>Internships aren’t just about work. With your first bit of income, do something fun. Try new things. Make memories. You’ll never get this time back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="blog" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="introduction" /><category term="blogging" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned from My Internship at Zlemma]]></summary></entry></feed>